alertid.com 2010-06-20

# AlertID.me - Privacy

**Security and Privacy Statement**

Legally, we’re required to issue and adhere to a fancy legalistic privacy policy. Our philosophy on privacy, however, is far simpler than all the legal speak that our attorneys so kindly drafted (below). We, the owners of AlertID, place a great value on our own personal privacy. We believe that your personal information is just as important as our own. So, we absolutely refuse to share your personal information with any unauthorized business, organization, or individual. We promise.

Keli and Eve   
Founders, AlertID

**Q**. How secure is the information about my child?   
**A.** Your family information is secure and available only to the right people at the right time. In addition to your child's safety, we take extreme measures on security, here's an overview on AlertID's security.

  1. AlertID is as secure as your online banking 
  2. AlertID only provides first responders the information they need in an emergency 
  3. AlertID uses powerful 128-bit encryption 
  4. AlertID records all first responder calls 
  5. AlertID records caller’s telephone number 
  6. AlertID’s data center is on a military grid to ensure security 
  7. AlertID monitors its data center 24/7/365 to guarantee security 

_____________________________________________________________________________

**Our Security and Privacy Promise to You**

AlertID cares about the security and privacy of our Members’ personal and medical information and places great value on the practice of safeguarding it. Trust and the desire for confidentiality are among the reasons why Members select AlertID as their choice for an emergency medical information and identification service.

AlertID is committed to ensuring the privacy of visitors and Members to its web site. The information gathering and dissemination practices for the web site owned and operated by AlertID are presented in this statement.

AlertID ensures that any and all personal and medical data are provided voluntarily by our Members. AlertID has always provided its Members with full disclosure regarding uses of their medical and personal information. AlertID obtains prior approval for all storage and transfer – electronic or otherwise – of Members’ information. AlertID has taken steps to protect Member information stored on its systems and to ensure that the “information loop” between Members, AlertID , and emergency personnel remains closed, thereby avoiding any breech of a Member’s confidence and security by other information “handlers” or processors. Our Members and the emergency personnel who serve them can be assured that personal and medical information remains secure, confidential, and used only for its authorized, intended purpose.

**Registration, Ordering and Updating Information**

AlertID ’s online registration process requires potential Members to provide minimal personal and financial information (Name, address and credit card number). Membership in AlertID authorizes us to release all medical and other confidential information you may provide us about you, in emergencies to appropriate emergency responders and to other health care personnel you designate. 

AlertID uses an order form for Members to purchase products and services. Information from the order form is used to ship orders, send information about AlertID Services and update the Member’s file. All Members can review, update and modify their personal medical information through the secure web site or by calling the AlertID Call Center at 1-877-590-Alert during business hours. Any changes entered by the Member will be reflected in the data-base upon successful submission. 

In setting up a membership for a child, the parent(s) or legal guardian(s) will provide medical information they want shared with emergency responders, health care personnel and others designated by them. This may include providing emergency contact information for people to be contacted if the child is alone in an emergency. 

AlertID depends on the information provided by the Member, or the Members parent(s) or legal guardian(s), and does not ask for additional information other than that necessary to provide emergency and health care information and to contact the Member regarding renewal of their subscription. 

Members, or parent(s) or legal guardian(s) of a child Member, can access their information for the purpose of correct and/or updating it online at www.AlertID.Me, through one of our Member Service Associates at 1-877-590-Alert, or by fax or mail. Changes to ones file will be made immediately if done through our 1-877-590-Alert number, or via our secure web site. 

**Notification of Changes**

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information, or that of a child’s, in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you, or the parent of the child, via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this manner, or the information of a child. However, if you have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated your account, then you will not be contacted. Nor will your personal information, or that of a child’s, be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our data-base, we will post a prominent notice on our web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

If a Member, or a parent(s) or legal guardian(s) of a Member who is a child wishes to delete their Member, or their child’s information and terminate their, or their child’s membership from AlertID they must do so by putting this request in writing and mailing it to AlertID. 

Upon receipt of the Member’s, or the Member parent’s or legal guardian(s), written request, the Member will be forwarded a Termination form within 48-hours to complete, sign and return to AlertID together with the emblem or attest to the fact that the emblem is not in the Member’s possession, but that the Member must return the emblem when the emblem comes back into his or her possession. Signing and returning the Termination form releases AlertID from all future obligations and responsibilities related to the provision of that Member’s medical information for any reason, including emergencies. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Our policies provide for the safeguarding of Members’ information and prohibit its distribution (selling, loaning or renting) to any party except for the purposes for which a Member has subscribed. AlertID will release Members’ personal, identifiable information only when we have permission to share the information for the use it is intended which might include relaying information to emergency personnel in medical emergencies to assist with the speed of treatment of Members. 

Although we make every effort to preserve your privacy we may need to disclose personal information when required by law where we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or other valid legal process.

In addition, if visitors and Members provide AlertID an e-mail address, the organization will use it to send electronic announcements of special promotions, news and educational related items or general communications. This feature is only available to visitors and Members who opt-in to subscribe to receive such information. Visitors or Members who wish to opt-out can do so by un-selecting the checkbox. For a child Member e-mails are directed to e-mail address on file and are intended for the parent(s) or legal guardian(s) of the Member.

**Non Personally Identifiable Information**

AlertID web site servers use log files. This information is not personally identifiable and may include user IP addresses, browser types, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This allows AlertID   
to analyze trends and gather data to help us to improve the web site. Log files are not tied to user’s personal information.

**Links**

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, AlertID , are not responsible for the privacy practices of other such sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site.

**Cookies**

In order to protect your privacy, AlertID.org uses session cookies only. No personal information is collected or stored in a cookie. Session cookies are used to allow a Member to make updates securely to his record. The session cookie is stored in memory and does not persist when the user logs off.

**Terms and Condition of Sales**

To review our terms and condition of sales, please click here.
